Guide to the George Whitmore Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Electronic Files, 1981-1986; Series VI
  The series contains fifty-eight 5-1/4-inch computer disks holding electronic versions of some of Whitmore's compositions, drafts, mailing lists, interview notes, journal entries, correspondence, and miscellaneous documents. The files were created using a Kaypro computer and WordStar software, a word processing system for text preparation. The disks were sequentially numbered by Beinecke staff before being sent out for conversion; these numbers are referenced throughout this finding aid. The disk and individual file titles were assigned by Whitmore.
  One Kaypro disk box and one Maxell mini-floppy disk box were retained with the disks.
  The collection also includes the original software disks that were shipped with the computer. A set of manuals and users guides issued by the company are filed in Series I, along with a single folder with manuscript and typed instructions created by Whitmore.
  The list that follows includes only the titles of electronic files with content created by Whitmore; no programming files are listed, nor are blank disks and entire disks of programming software (numbers 32-35, 37-40, 42, 44, and 50-58).
  - Disk 1 (labeled: Someone was Here, Envelopes & Wordstar)
    - ENV, undated
    - INDEX, undated
    - INVITES, undated
    - LABEL, undated
  - Disk 2 (labeled: Disk 1 General, Someone was Here Preface, etc...)
    - AIINDEX.BAK, undated
    - ARTICLE, undated
    - EPIGRAPH, undated
    - EPILOGUE, undated
    - GENINDEX, undated
    - HEAD, undated
    - INDEX, undated
    - PREFACE, undated
    - PSEUDON, 1987 Feb 24
    - PTLIST, 1987 Feb 24
    - REPORTING, undated
    - STYLE, undated
    - STYLE.BAK, undated
  - Disk 3 (labeled: Disk 2 Preface, Someone was Here, Jim & Edward)
    - 28, undated
    - 33, undated
    - TEXT1, undated
    - TEXT2, undated
    - TEXT3, undated
    - TEXT4, undated
    - TEXT5, undated
    - TEXT6, undated
  - Disk 4 (labeled: Disk 3 Someone was Here, Jim & Edward 2)
    - STATS, 1985 Apr 21
    - TEXT7, undated
    - TEXT8, undated
    - TEXT9, undated
  - Disk 5 (labeled: Disk 4 Someone was Here, Mrs. Rocha)
    - 123, undated
    - ADD, undated
    - INDEX, undated
    - TEXT10, undated
    - TEXT11, undated
    - TEXT12, undated
    - TEXT13, undated
    - TEXT14, undated
    - TEXT15, undated
  - Disk 6 (labeled: Disk 5 Someone was Here, Lincoln Hosp 1)
    - 149, undated
    - 164, undated
    - ADD, undated
    - HEAD, undated
    - INDEX, undated
    - JUDY, undated
    - TEXT16, undated
    - TEXT17, undated
    - TEXT18, undated
    - TEXT19, undated
    - TEXT20, undated
  - Disk 7 (Labeled: Disk 6 Someone was Here, Lincoln Hosp 2, epilogue)
    - INDEX, undated
    - OLDPILO, undated
    - REVEPILO, undated
    - TEXT21, undated
    - TEXT22, undated
    - TEXT23, undated
    - TEXT24, undated
  - Disk 8 (labeled: AIDS Backup 1, 1985)
    - DENNIS.$$$, 1985 Feb 24
    - ED217.NTS, 1985 Feb 17
    - ED217.QUO, undated
    - ED221.NTS, 1985 Feb 21
    - ED221.QUO, 1985 Feb 21
    - JIM215.QUO, undated
    - JIM.NTS, 1985 Feb 14
  - Disk 9 (labeled: AIDS Backup 2, 1985)
    - CAIAZZA, 1985 Feb 28
    - DENNIS, 1985 Feb 24
    - ED313, 1985 Mar 13
    - J&E-31, 1985 Mar 1
    - JIM225, 1985 Feb 25
    - MCFARLAN, 1985 Mar 6
    - PSYCH, undated
    - SENCER, 1985 Mar 18
    - WEIN, 1985 Mar 4
  - Disk 10 (labeled: AIDS Backup 3, 1985)
    - CONSENT, undated
    - CONSENT.BAK, undated
    - CONSENT.PWA, undated
    - DENN.QUO, undated
    - ED.QUO, undated
    - EXPENSES, undated
    - EXPERTS, undated
    - INTERV, undated
    - JIM.QUO, undated
    - LEAD.OLD, undated
    - OLD.TXT, undated
    - PHONE, undated
    - QUOTES, undated
    - STATS, undated
    - TEXT1, undated
    - TEXT2, undated
    - TEXT3, undated
    - TEXT4, undated
    - TIMES.COR, undated
    - YOU.JIM, undated
  - Disk 11 (labeled: AIDS Backup 4, Final copy, 1985)
    - 1, undated
    - 2, undated
    - 3, undated
    - 4, undated
    - DENIAL, undated
    - DOCTOR, undated
    - INTERV, undated
    - PHOBIAS, undated
    - PHONE, undated
    - STATS, undated
    - YOU, undated
  - Disk12 (labeled: Backup-ws)
    - ENV, undated
    - EXCERPT, undated
    - LABEL, undated
  - Disk13 (labeled: Backup, Nebraska 1)
    - NEB1A, undated
    - NEB1B, undated
    - NEB2, undated
    - NEB3, undated
    - NEB4, undated
    - NEB5, undated
    - NEB6, undated
  - Disk14 (labeled: Backup, Nebraska 2)
    - FILE, undated
    - NEB1, undated
    - NEB2, undated
    - NEB3, undated
    - NEB4, undated
  - Disk15 (labeled: Backup, Nebraska 3)
    - INDEX, undated
    - NEB1, undated
    - NEB2, undated
    - NEB3, undated
    - NEB4, undated
    - NEB5, undated
    - NEB6, undated
  - Disk16 (labeled: SWH Backup #1)
    - AINDEX.BAK, undated
    - ARTICLE, undated
    - EPIGRAPH, undated
    - EPILOGUE, undated
    - GENINDEX, undated
    - HEAD, undated
    - INDEX, undated
    - PREFACE, undated
    - PSEUDON, undated
    - PTLIST, undated
    - REPORTING, undated
    - STYLE, undated
  - Disk17 (labeled: TOM AIDS GQ Essay 12/85)
    - BAR, undated
    - BLOOD, undated
    - CAF, undated
    - CHARLES, undated
    - CHRIS, undated
    - CUT, undated
    - CUT2, undated
    - EDDIE, undated
    - ENV, undated
    - FOOT, undated
    - HORATIO, undated
    - HOSP, undated
    - JIM, undated
    - LUNCH, undated
    - MAN, undated
    - NUMBERS, undated
    - OWEN, undated
    - PAST, undated
    - PAUL, 1984 Nov 27
    - PHOTOS, undated
    - PUB, undated
    - RESEARCH, undated
    - SPOT, undated
    - TEXT1, undated
    - TEXT2, undated
    - THOMAS, undated
    - TOM1, undated
    - TV, undated
  - Disk 18 (labeled: AIDS Copy, NY Times 5/85, unedited text)
    - STATS, undated
    - TEXT1, undated
    - TEXT2, undated
  - Disk 19 (labeled: SWH Backup #2)
    - HEAD, undated
    - TEXT1, undated
    - TEXT2, undated
    - TEXT3, undated
    - TEXT4, undated
    - TEXT5, undated
    - TEXT6, undated
  - Disk 20 (labeled: SWH Backup 3)
    - HEAD, undated
    - STATS, undated
    - TEXT7, undated
    - TEXT8, undated
    - TEXT9, undated
  - Disk 21 (labeled: SWH Backup #4)
    - INDEX, undated
    - TEXT10, undated
    - TEXT11, undated
    - TEXT12, undated
    - TEXT13, undated
    - TEXT14, undated
    - TEXT15, undated
  - Disk 22 (labeled: SWH Backup #5)
    - HEAD, undated
    - INDEX, undated
    - TEXT16, undated
    - TEXT17, undated
    - TEXT18, undated
    - TEXT19, undated
    - TEXT20, undated
  - Disk 23 (labeled: SWH Backup #6)
    - INDEX, undated
    - OLDEPILO, undated
    - TEXT21, undated
    - TEXT22, undated
    - TEXT23, undated
    - TEXT24, undated
  - Disk 24 (labeled: Nebraska 1)
    - NEB1A, undated
    - NEB1B, undated
    - NEB2, undated
    - NEB3, undated
    - NEB4, undated
    - NEB5, undated
    - NEB6, undated
  - Disk 25 (labeled: Nebraska 2)
    - FILE, undated
    - NEB1, undated
    - NEB2, undated
    - NEB3, undated
    - NEB4, undated
  - Disk 26 (labeled: Nebraska 3)
    - INDEX, undated
    - NEB1, undated
    - NEB2, undated
    - NEB3, undated
    - NEB4, undated
    - NEB5, undated
    - NEB6, undated
  - Disk 27 (labeled: Nebraska Rewrites 12/86)
    - MARY, undated
  - Disk 28 (labeled: Working disk K1)
    - BEIGE, 1987 Mar 22
    - ENV, undated
    - KELLY, undated
    - STALKER, undated
  - Disk 29 (labeled: WORDSTAR K-1)
    - ENV, undated
    - GEO, undated
    - LABEL, undated
    - LTR, undated
    - POEM, undated
    - PRINT.TST, undated
    - WILL, undated
    - X, undated
  - Disk 30 (labeled: ALL MADE SAFE #1)
    - HEAD.BAK, undated
    - NTS, undated
    - SAFE1, undated
  - Disk 31 (labeled: Proposals K-1)
    - BEIGE, 1987 Mar 22
    - BURRELL, undated
    - CALKE, undated
    - ENV, undated
    - LABEL, undated
    - STALKER, undated
  - Disk 36 (labeled: Backup Articles 2)
    - BIKE, undated
    - HOUGHTON, undated
    - LADYCINT, 1985 Jul 18
    - LADYCQUO, 1985 Jul
    - LADYCTXT, undated
  - Disk 41 (labeled: AIDS 1986-7)
    - ARBOR, 1985 Sep 4
    - BOOKS, undated
    - COMPLIST, undated
    - CONSENT.ANO, undated
    - CONSENT.MD, undated
    - CONSENT.REG, undated
    - ENV, undated
    - GHOST, undated
    - GWENV, undated
    - HEAD, undated
    - INDEX, undated
    - INTERVWS, undated
    - INVITES, undated
    - JONES, 1988 Mar 16
    - LABEL, undated
    - LINC.ENV, undated
    - LTR, 1988 Apr 23
    - LUKE.ENV, undated
    - PR, undated
    - ROCHA.ENV, undated
    - SHARP, 1988 Apr 29
    - TIMES.ART, undated
    - TIMES.NTS, undated
  - Disk 43 (labeled: Correspondence & Proposals & Copy)
    - 7DAYS, undated
    - ACOUST, 1986 Sep 5
    - BURRELL, undated
    - CALKE, 1987 Jan 14
    - CANOVA, 1986 Jun 10
    - CHISWICK.BAK, 1984 Sep 19
    - COLORS, 1986 Dec 11
    - DRUGS, undated
    - DUBLIN, undated
    - ENV, undated
    - GLASCOW, undated
    - GROVE.BIO, 1986 Jan 4
    - HETLOO, undated
    - JO, 1986 Sep 20
    - JO.ENV, undated
    - KILTS, 1987 Feb 26
    - LABEL, undated
    - MUSEUMS, 1985 Oct 15
    - ORSAY, 1986 Oct 7
    - PARIS, undated
    - RESUME.BAK, undated
    - RUSSBORO.BAK, 1984 Oct 4
    - STALKER, undated
    - SWORD, 1984 Oct 16
    - SYBIL, 1986 Nov 18
    - TAPES, 1984 Nov 12
    - TENEMENT, undated
    - THOREAU, undated
    - TILLINGE, undated
    - WEIMAR, undated
  - Disk 45 (labeled: Articles Copy)
    - A&C.NTS, undated
    - A&C.QUO, undated
    - A&C.TXT, undated
    - BEIGE, 1988 Feb 19
    - CAB, 1986 Nov 11
    - CABTXT, undated
    - ENV, undated
    - FESTIVAL, undated
    - GALV, undated
    - GALV2, undated
    - GREYTXT, undated
    - H&G, undated
    - INVOICE, undated
    - LABEL, undated
    - MANINC, 1987 Mar 30
    - VOGUE, undated
  - Disk 46 (labeled: Acoust. Barge, Broadcasting...)
    - ACOUST, undated
    - BARGE.TXT, undated
    - BROAD.TXT, undated
    - DESIGN, undated
    - ENV, undated
    - MONAGHAN, undated
    - SHELLY, 1987 Apr 13
    - STREETS, undated
    - TILLINT, 1987 Jan 14
    - TWEEDS, undated
    - TWEEDS.NTS, undated
  - Disk 47 (labeled: Journal)
    - APR12, 1985 Apr 12
    - APR7, 1985 Apr 7
    - APR9, 1985 Apr 9
    - ENG1, 1985 Jul
    - ENG2, 1985 Jul
    - ENG3, 1985 Jul
    - MAIN, 1985 Jul 12
    - MAR30, 1986 Mar 30
    - MAY11, 1985 May 11
    - SEPT11, 1985 Sep 11
    - SEPT30, 1985 Sep 30
    - SHIRT, undated
  - Disk 48 (labeled: WordStar)
    - ENV, undated
    - JAY, 1987 May 22
  - Disk 49 (labeled: Backup Articles)
    - ASHNTS.$$$, undated
    - DEVERE.TXT, undated
    - LABEL, undated
    - LABEL.BAK, undated
    - RAMTXT2, 1985 Oct 5
    - SILKS, undated
    - THORN.TXT, undated
- Oversize, 3; (2 boxes)
  - AIDS information (in Series I), 1985-1989 (Box 18, Folder 245)
  - Emma Morris Free Milk Fund (in Series I), 1972 (Box 18, Folder 246)
  - Interviews and profiles (in Series I), 1980 Apr 16 (Box 18, Folder 247)
  - MacDowell Colony residency (in Series I), 1985-1987 (Box 18, Folder 248)
  - Confessions of Danny Slocum, St. Martins Press edition (in Series II), 1980 Jun 2 (Box 18, Folder 249)
  - Confessions of Danny Slocum, Grey Fox Press edition (in Series II), 1986 Mar 24 (Box 18, Folder 250)
  - Deep Dish (in Series II), photocopies for patron use, 1980-1982 (Box 18, Folder 251)
  - Deep Dish (in Series II), printed versions for parts 1-18, 20-26, 1980-1982 (Box 18, Folder 252-255)
  - Nebraska reviews (in Series II), 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 256)
  - The Caseworker (in Series II), stage designs, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 257)
  - The Rights (in Series II), 1983 (Box 18, Folder 258)
  - Two Plays for Three Women: Flight/The Legacy (in Series II), 1979 (Box 18, Folder 259)
  - Cripple Creek (in Series II), 1973-1976 (Box 18, Folder 260)
  - Getting Gay In New York, and other poems (in Series II), printed versions from Fag Rag, 1974, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 261)
  - Getting Gay In New York, and other poems (in Series II), reviews, 1976-1978 (Box 18, Folder 262)
  - "In the Fall of States" (in Series II), 1979 (Box 18, Folder 263)
  - "Alvah" (in Series II), 1981 Oct 18 (Box 18, Folder 264)
  - "How to Marry a Zillionaire," published in Alternate (in Series II), undated (Box 18, Folder 265)
  - The Advocate (in Series III), on Howard Brown, 1975 Feb 26 (Box 19, Folder 266)
  - The Advocate (in Series III), literature column, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 267)
  - The Advocate (in Series III), miscellaneous clippings, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 268)
  - Bay Area Reporter (in Series III), 1981 Jun 4 (Box 19, Folder 269)
  - Berkeley Barb (in Series III), 1974 Jun (Box 19, Folder 270)
  - Body Politic (in Series III), 1978, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 271)
  - Boston Gay Review (in Series III), 1978 fall (Box 19, Folder 272)
  - Gay Community News (in Series III), 1978-1980 (Box 19, Folder 273)
  - Gay Sunshine (in Series III), 1977 (Box 19, Folder 274)
  - Gaysweek (in Series III), 1977-1979 (Box 19, Folder 275)
  - Harper's Weekly (in Series III), 1975 Sep 1 (Box 19, Folder 276)
  - New York Times (in Series III), 1983 (Box 19, Folder 277)
  - Soho Weekly News (in Series III), 1975 (Box 19, Folder 278)
  - Village Voice, "New Faces: John Kelly" (in Series III), 1988 Jun 28 (Box 19, Folder 279)
  - "Reaching Out to Someone with AIDS," fan mail (in Series IV), 1985 May-Jun (Box 19, Folder 280)
  - "Bearing Witness," proofs (in Series IV), 1988 Jan (Box 19, Folder 281)
  - Someone Was Here: Profiles in the AIDS Epidemic, reviews (in Series IV), 1988 (Box 19, Folder 282)
  - Burroughs, William S. (in Series V), 1981 Feb 18 (Box 19, Folder 283)
  - Civilian Conservation Corps (in Series V), 1980 (Box 19, Folder 284)
  - England (in Series V), 1984-1987 (Box 19, Folder 285)
  - Everard Baths fire (in Series V), 1977-1978 (Box 19, Folder 286-287)
  - Ireland (in Series V), 1988 (Box 19, Folder 288)
  - Italy (in Series V), 1986 Feb 2 (Box 19, Folder 289)
  - Varnedoe, Kirk (in Series V), 1988 (Box 19, Folder 290)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Boxes 20 and 21 hold Restricted Fragile material that may be seen only with permission of the curator.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies available. Consult access services for further information.
  - Box 5, folder 65 (Box 20, Folder 291)
  - Box 5, folder 67 (Box 20, Folder 292)
  - Box 7, folder 91 (Box 20, Folder 293)
  - Box 11, folder 145 (Box 20, Folder 294)
  - Box 11, folder 152 (Box 20, Folder 295)
  - Box 16, folder 234a (Box 20, Folder 296)
  - Series VI: Disks 1-10 (Box 21, Folder 297)
  - Series VI: Disks 11-20 (Box 21, Folder 298)
  - Series VI: Disks 21-30 (Box 21, Folder 299)
  - Series VI: Disks 31-40 (Box 21, Folder 300)
  - Series VI: Disks 41-44, in Kaypro diskettes box (Box 21, Folder 301)
  - Series VI: Disks 45-58, in Maxell mini-floppy disk box (Box 21, Folder 302)